MARRIAGE PROPOSAL
I'm a widow.
I know.
And you're the Grand Prince.
Who cares?
People will call it immoral and mock us.
Let them.
Let's go.
Don't take that hand.
You're not allowed to leave.
You can't leave this house
until you die.
Move.
Unlike the noble Grand Prince,
I can become petty very easily.
She belongs to this family,
so she can't leave this house
until she dies.
If I were to be petty,
everyone in this house,
except Hong Eun-jo, would leave dead.
Dae-chu, my sword.
Bring it on.
Drop the titles.
Drop the ranks.
Drop the honorifics.
- You know how to fight?
- You're still talking?
What are you doing? Let's just go.
I never turn down a challenge.
I like that.
Officer Seo, are you just
going to stand there and watch?
Boys grow up fighting.
If I win, Hong Eun-jo will die
a natural death in this house.
And if I win,
she will live
a long, healthy life in my house.
You're acting like children.
Look, both of you,
I decide where I die!
Agreed?
- Agreed.
- What?
If either of you
can actually wield a sword--
You're good with a sword.
And you've got some strength.
What are you doing?
My lord.
How did you…
Eun-jo, follow me.
Oh, dear.
What do I do?
What's this sound?
Did you say Father's back?
Could you go and stop him? Please.
Father!
You…
I knew you would do this.
You really made Father…
No, Father!
Please! Enough already!
As her father, this is my fault.
Her father?
You keep saying that
to a concubine's daughter.
That's why she thinks
she can get her way in everything!
She lied to all of us about her marriage!
But it's not too late.
I will discipline her properly.
As a slave.
You, come out.
Come out!
You think I can't do it, right?
Move.
How pathetic.
I'm sick of this!
How long have you been here?
The whole time.
Leave.
I don't want us to look close.
Same here.
Leave, will you?
This is where I live.
Think about for whom
it would make more sense
to stand here by this wall.
Think about who would look cooler
standing by this wall.
The battle isn't over yet.
The judge will decide the winner,
not the sword.
You picked the wrong opponent.
I don't think so. My skills never fail me.
And I never give up.
Sorry to interrupt you
in the middle of a fight,
but you're not just going to stand there
until one of you leaves, right?
This isn't about your ego, right?
Not at all.
Never.
You've been standing like that
over an hour. Your leg must be numb.
Your back must hurt.
All right. How about this?
I'll count to three,
and then you'll go your separate ways.
All right. One.
Two.
Three!
Three and a half!
Four!
Wow, you had to go on four
so you wouldn't lose.
When it comes to childishness,
you two are tied.
My arm hurts.
I found out everything the day
before the wedding, and still let her go.
You should blame me.
Where is Eun-jo?
I told her to get some air.
I told her to go outside and cool down.
Hello!
Come and take a look at our ornaments.
Come on, Lady.
Come here.
Oh, my.
How about something like this?
Let's just see how it looks on you.
Oh, my.
It really brings out your features.
This is perfect for you.
How pretty.
Your face is glowing.
It's out-of-this-world beauty.
Do you want to try it?
Swing high
and leave all your worries in the sky.
I don't want to.
Hong-si seems fine.
She probably isn't.
It's because you buried everything
beneath the words "I'm fine."
You buried your heart.
She must be hiding her feelings again,
behind her calm face,
burying them all.
- Let's check out other places too.
- Sure.
Why are you following me around?
Well…
So I could pull you out
if you get lost in thought
and fall into a ditch,
pour you another drink
if you feel like one,
and pat your shoulder if you cry.
When did you notice?
It's hard to miss someone that tall.
I tried my best not to stand out,
but you got me.
The reason I sent the letter
to Lord Hong was…
What was the reason?
As the Grand Prince of this kingdom,
I meant to set right the wrongful marriage
and correct misguided customs.
I see.
And someone like that
sent a letter in my name.
I did?
I was in your body
when I wrote the letter.
I must have written your name by accident.
I see.
My name was written by my hand.
I know.
I was being rash again.
Hit me. I can take a hit.
Be gentle.
I'm not doing that.
I understand.
You were about to live as a widow,
not knowing when it would end.
Of course you wanted to find a way
to escape that family.
It had to happen at some point.
I'm relieved we switched back
before it was too late.
Are you all right?
Then it's fine.
This is
my proposal.
MARRIAGE PROPOSAL
And…
You said you're all right.
That's all I need to hear today.
I'm sorry I couldn't be of help.
I'm the one who should apologize
for asking such a big favor.
Look here, Min-jik.
Why, if it isn't my cousin!
I was actually thinking
about visiting you after work.
Funny running into you here.
I should be on my way, or I'll be late.
I'm truly grateful.
As I said, it's because
he saved my life on the battlefield.
You must be Eun-jo.
Yes, sir.
Don't trouble yourself to see me out.
Please tell Min-jik
that I enjoyed my visit.
Yes, sir.
Eun-jo,
it's over now.
What do you mean?
As Your Highness commanded,
I said that it was easy money
from selling the land.
Let's keep this between us.
May I ask why?
I just hope
it will make things a little easier.
Pardon?
I heard that in the Gyeongo Year,
Lord Hong Min-jik had all his property
confiscated by the royal court.
Consider this its return.
My lord,
where are you coming from?
I'm sorry.
Did you…
Did you give all the land we received
from the lord from Naju
to the Chief Secretary's family?
Please take it back.
That marriage was my choice--
It was neither your choice
nor your responsibility
nor
your marriage.
It was my mistake.
With that land, we could live
the rest of our lives comfortably--
Enough.
Do not disgrace yourself anymore.
I have never treated you that way.
If you
truly wish to do good to me,
treat yourself with respect.
Whatever happened in that family,
forget it all.
And please forgive
your foolish father.
As you wished,
I've left it all behind me.
You must be hungry.
I will help my mother
and prepare the meal.
MARRIAGE PROPOSAL
My Grand Prince Dowol
is a grown-up now, but has no spouse.
Thus, a formal marriage proposal is made
according to tradition. Please accept.
"Grand Prince Dowol"?
It was Your Highness
who sent for Lord Hong?
He was the Minister of War
of this kingdom.
I hear he led countless battles to victory
in the north.
As a man of virtue
living upon the land he has protected,
it is only right to wish him well,
and for his family
to live comfortably.
Are you sure it wasn't for Hong-si?
She only happens to be the daughter
of the man I wish well.
So it was for Physician Hong.
What? What's wrong?
Lord Hong Min-jik
was dismissed by His Majesty
in the Gyeongo Year.
The royal family
is practically the enemy of his family.
HYEMINSEO
Thank you.
You came back just in time.
Go back to work.
Yes, sir.
I'm so glad
that stupid marriage fell through!
I can finally enjoy a drink
when I'm on night duty.
That's what you're happy about?
I was going to drink with you too, dear.
What? "Dear"?
What, you boor?
- Dear?
- Boor?
Be quiet!
Eun-jo, I'm so happy for you.
Have you two already seen a physician?
Yes.
My stomach's been aching a little,
so I came to see if it was the plague.
But it turns out it was only constipation.
My head was spinning,
so I thought it was the plague…
You're just hung over.
You saw it too, right?
These days,
half the patients are like this.
I blame the false rumors
spreading through the capital.
I'm worried about the people
outside the capital.
I can't believe there's a plague.
If the plague spreads into the capital,
it will unsettle the people.
Plague comes every year.
If we let it be,
it will die down on its own.
My concern is that whenever His Majesty
goes hunting to Onyang,
the court is left unattended for too long.
Perhaps we should establish
a hunting ground closer to the capital.
There are people's dwellings and farmlands
around the capital.
That will not be allowed.
You should have made an appointment.
His Highness is out of the palace
at the moment.
Please inform him that I wish to see him
regarding my daughter.
I can't stop coughing today.
You should go to the Royal Pharmacy.
My physician has left to accompany
His Majesty on his hunting trip.
I've had asthma since I was young.
I've lived in your body,
and there was no lingering illness.
You have a perfectly healthy body.
It started a few days ago.
Did you get hurt
in the fight the other day?
- Let me see.
- I'm not hurt.
It merely tickles.
I'm more worried about him.
If I have a small injury like this,
he must have nearly died.
Why did you even fight?
The only way to deal
with those bent on bullying you
is to ignore them.
He's so twisted.
I almost feel sorry for him.
Do you think
that's why he didn't let you go?
What else could it be?
You don't want to know.
Shall we go eat?
All of a sudden?
You've been working all day.
You have no patients, no family,
and no husband.
I'm sure you have nothing
in your stomach either.
He knows that my marriage fell through.
By any chance…
Your Highness?
It's really you.
What an unexpected place to meet you.
How many other women were you seeing
while you were in my body?
It wasn't me.
I knew you wouldn't remember me.
I'm Chief State Councilor
Han Seung-rok's daughter, Ji-yeon.
Right, we've met before, at the palace.
Yes, Your Highness.
I've heard that
Your Highness has rejected
every lady in the capital.
What brings you here?
There's a plague going around.
My father sent me to deliver
some medicinal herbs to the Hyeminseo.
That's typical of him.
Please give him my regards.
Yes, Your Highness.
This thing is full. What's inside?
Give it back.
Come on.
We're going in the same direction.
Maybe I should ask her
to cook the broody hen today.
What?
Are you going to see my mother?
Right.
I called her "Mother" for a while,
in a way, she's my mother.
About your marriage proposal--
This isn't the place for that talk.
Later.
Let's eat first.
No.
Listen to me.
You should be with someone
who befits your title as Grand Prince.
Why should I, when I have you?
Someone who?
Don't act like you don't understand me.
Someone like
the Chief State Councilor's daughter.
Are you jealous?
No, I'm not.
My mother forced me to meet her.
And it was only once.
I didn't ask.
Could you at least pretend to be curious?
I'm saying this for your sake.
If you really want what's good for me,
cook the broody hen for me.
Why don't you ask the Chief Royal Cook?
Wait, where are you going?
You forgot this.
Keep up this bickering
and your families won't just be enemies,
they'll be archenemies.
Well, I guess most people in love
end up enemies.
That's very natural.
Is that what you're hoping for?
Jealous?
That's nonsense.
If this is about the broody hen again,
go away.
I really…
Goodness gracious!
Physician Hong, it's me.
It's you. You scared me.
I needed the headscarf
to get into the capital.
If anyone recognizes me,
I'll be in trouble.
Who are you?
He's someone I know.
Why are you dressed like a woman?
Something happened at the leper camp,
so I came to ask Physician Hong for help.
Leper camp?
So, the plague started at the leper camp?
Plague?
That's what the physician
from Hwalinseo said
when he came by yesterday.
Some have been vomiting
and also running high fevers.
What's the diagnosis?
We don't know.
So they haven't even been
properly examined.
The Hwalinseo was established
to deal with plagues and provide relief.
Most people avoid the leper camp,
even physicians.
And I'm no different,
even though I have to live there
because of my ill family.
Physician Hong is the only one
willing to help us.
Shall we hurry?
Wait, give us a moment.
What's the matter?
This is where we treat patients.
There's a risk of infection.
I'm a physician who treats people,
and it's my responsibility
to control who enters this place.
Please follow her advice.
I'll get going.
Dae-chu,
go and find out
which physician came by the leper camp.
Yes, Your Highness.
We grouped those
with the same symptoms together.
Let me take a look.
It's tasty.
Stop.
It's dirty.
Spit it out.
It's our food.
Are you hungry too?
Do you want some?
I…
I saw the man you came with
on that hill over there.
Thank you.
To the right.
- To the right?
- Yes.
There.
There are so many here.
Good.
Geum-dol, come down.
How did it go?
I'll explain on the way.
I'll be right back.
Brother, are you coming back too?
Yes.
"Brother"?
So, the water
they drew from the valley went bad?
They drank it without knowing,
and now they've all come down
with dysentery.
It'll take a while to notify the Hyeminseo
and secure the necessary herbs.
My lord.
It seems you have urgent business
at the Hyeminseo.
Eun-jo, go ahead.
In the meantime,
I'll have a word with this gentleman.
I won't cause any trouble.
There are patients waiting for you.
I'll go ahead then.
I thought I might land a post at court
through your brother's connections,
but my father messed it up.
I can't believe he broke off her marriage
and let her work at the Hyeminseo again.
She works at the Hyeminseo?
She must be getting nosy again,
playing physician and all.
She'd better worry about me
rather than some random people.
What a wench.
Isn't it a good thing?
What?
Worrying about others.
My lord, you're back.
Yes.
Could you prepare some tea?
Yes, my lord.
It'll be ready shortly.
I failed to recognize
Your Highness the other day,
now that you are fully grown.
Please forgive my discourtesy.
You may speak freely.
MARRIAGE PROPOSAL
Please stop visiting Eun-jo.
If it's because of His Majesty--
Do not try to persuade me.
I apologize
for what happened with His Majesty.
- I've been nothing but sincere--
- That's exactly what I don't like.
Whoever you're with
will be at His Majesty's mercy.
Your sincerity is
exactly what makes her useful
to His Majesty.
I will not send Eun-jo
to the palace
where nothing but death awaits her.
And especially not
through marriage.
If that's the reason,
I can leave the palace to protect her--
No.
Please do nothing.
That is the only way
to protect Eun-jo.
What if I must do it anyway?
What if I push for it despite everything?
If you persist, despite everything,
I will tell Eun-jo
her marriage would mean my death.
And if you go so far
as to actually carry out this marriage,
I will truly take my own life
to stop it.
I don't want to hurt Eun-jo either.
Please, I humbly ask for your help.
You're still here.
How was it at the leper camp?
I took care of the urgent cases.
The Hyeminseo was kind enough
to supply me with plenty of herbs.
That's great to hear.
The Superintendent said
the herbs were bestowed
by the Grand Prince,
and that I should thank the royal court.
Thank you.
By the way,
what did you talk about with my lord?
Just exchanged greetings.
He saw me at the palace when I was young,
although I don't remember it.
So he knows you're the Grand Prince?
He knew.
I see.
Right.
Geum-dol was looking for you,
calling you "brother."
What did you do to him?
I guess my charm slipped out.
Do you always leave your charm
everywhere you go?
Yes, just so you can pick it up.
Why don't you pick it up yourself?
You're the one who left it behind.
I'm not sure if I could.
There's just too much charm.
Where does your confidence come from?
I learned it.
It's part of the royal education.
So that self-praise is learned.
Why are you smiling?
Why do you keep smiling?
Nothing.
I just want to keep smiling with you.
Today, I'll do it as much as I can.
Young Master, you're here again.
What is it?
The First Young Master ordered me
to burn everything in this room.
Leave it.
It's still
warm in there.
Yes, Young Master.
What? The marriage proposal…
Where did I drop it?
I'm so clumsy.
Did you lose something?
No, my lord.
I heard that
you met the Grand Prince at the Hyeminseo.
His Highness has a kind heart,
and has helped me on several occasions.
He's only fulfilling his duties
as a member of the royal family.
Yes, my lord.
Do you remember what you said?
I wish to live here with you and Mother
for the rest of my life.
I have never wanted a woman's life.
Do you still feel that way?
Yes, my lord.
Then do that.
My lady, I'm coming in.
A letter from the palace?
Is it Her Majesty the Queen Consort?
What?
The Queen Dowager wishes to see me.
Where's the Grand Prince?
We sent a man to his residence,
so he'll soon…
His Highness is here.
What is it you wish to say?
You look well put together.
This will suffice.
Are we expecting someone?
I'm not in the mood to meet anyone today.
It's not just anyone.
It's your impetuous companion
from the other day.
Lady Hae-rim of the Shin family is here.
From now on, remember that name.
It's the name of the woman
you had a night's fun with.
Hae-rim of the Shin family is present,
Her Majesty.
I believe I don't need
to introduce my son to you.
Yes, Your Majesty.
Have a seat.
I apologize for what I'm about to say.
Your Majesty,
there was a misunderstanding.
I hear you're the Queen Consort's niece.
We're in-laws?
I though Your Highness knew.
Kids, mind yourselves.
I heard your engagement
fell through recently.
Was it perhaps
because of the Grand Prince?
- Pardon?
- No need to answer that.
That is an improper question.
Even words of comfort
could be too much for her now.
How could you ask her that?
What I said the other day
was nothing but a bluff.
I'm afraid I have dishonored you.
I will explain in private.
Please stand up.
Yes, Your Highness.
Sit down.
Yes, Your Majesty.
I'll keep it short.
You both enjoyed what you were doing,
so no need to talk about who is to blame.
Just get married.
It makes us double in-laws,
a great blessing for the royal family.
I'm saying this now
only because I don't want you to persist
in troubling this lady
of the Queen Consort's family.
I have
someone I hold dear.
Forget her and move on.
I can never forget her.
That is my answer.
Find out when Hong-si
comes back from sick leave.
If she's recovered,
send her to me at once.
When you said
you stained my name the other day,
is this what you meant?
Probably.
What happened that day
and today are my fault.
I apologize.
His eyes are on another woman.
I wonder who she is.
Who is the woman
reflected in his shining eyes?
I'm seeing improvements.
That's wonderful.
Thank you for your help.
Eun-jo!
What is it?
Over there!
What's there?
What's that?
The rice grew on our food tree.
This is enough to feed us
for a whole year.
Who gave us precious rice?
FILL THE LEPER CAMP'S GRANARY WITH THIS
Was it the Grand Prince?
I'm not sure if we can really take it.
You need to eat well to regain strength.
That must be
what whoever sent this hoped for.
Gil-dong!
What? Gil-dong?
It must be him.
It seems like Gil-dong
is looking after us as well.
They said he stole
thousands of rice sacks, and it was true.
It was true.
No, you're all completely mistaken.
Gil-dong was a petty thief
who stole small things.
And Gil-dong is dead already.
Hello?
Can you hear me?
Eun-jo, did Gil-dong come back to life?
I'm a physician, and I'm telling you,
once you're dead, it's over.
You can't come back.
No, Gil-dong never dies.
Now he's immortal?
Oh, dear.
Is this going to start another rumor?
I thought
everyone in this world wanted us dead.
But it seems this person
wants us to keep living.
Just like you, Physician Hong.
What?
I didn't do anything.
Leper camp?
If we move this leper camp here,
and make this entire area
a hunting ground, including the forest,
hardly any homes will be affected.
I agree.
Does the king really need
a new hunting ground?
Every time he goes hunting,
Father has to accompany him
to the Onyang Royal Villa.
And it's a hassle.
Because it makes it harder for you
to manage the court.
Look at you, all grown up.
By the way,
why did Hong Min-jik have to appear
and cause trouble when Father is away?
He cleared the debt with land.
Where did he get it from?
It's his cousin's land.
That lowly girl
should have stayed with our family.
Why is that?
Father is keeping an eye on Hong Min-jik.
That girl would've made a hostage,
in a way.
If it's not our grandfather,
it should be fine.
What do you mean?
We can give her what she was expecting.
What was she expecting?
That vile girl as my concubine?
Are you crazy?
Wait.
If not me,
what about you?
You won't be able
to see His Highness for a while.
He can't leave the palace
because of the Royal School.
I see.
His Highness sent rice
to the leper camp, right?
I came to offer my thanks.
Please pass them along.
Did you hear that?
Gil-dong came back to life!
Did he really come back from the dead?
He's immortal!
Wait.
- Is that rumor true?
- What?
That he took rice to the leper camp.
Leper camp?
Eun-jo's been going there a lot lately.
I wonder if she saw Gil-dong.
I told you.
There is nowhere in Joseon
that Gil-dong's hands cannot reach!
Gil-dong is incredible!
I see you came to offer your prayers.
The lord returned safely,
so I came to offer my prayers of thanks.
This is my daughter
whom you've always wanted to see.
I'm Hong Eun-jo.
Could you give me the names
of your family members?
I would like to offer prayers for them.
That is so generous of you.
HONG MIN-JIK, HONG DAE-IL
HONG EUN-JO, CHUN-SEOM
I appreciate your kindness.
They say, before Gyeongo Year,
Lord Hong's benevolence
reached everyone in the capital.
I was one of them.
Do you know
what kind of person the current king is?
I do not know much
about the affairs of those in high places.
I'm a mere commoner,
struggling to get by every day.
You should know.
That man held a blade
to Lord Hong's throat.
A blade?
That was in the Gyeongo Year,
the bloody year.
Punishing them based solely on the appeal
would bring great misfortune
upon Your Majesty in the future.
Lord Hong nearly lost his life
for offering frank counsel.
Punishing immoral writings
is right and necessary.
And Im Sa-hyeong,
who was a mere censor at the time,
saved his life with honeyed words.
Encouraged by those honeyed words,
the king ruthlessly purged all officials
who would not bend to him,
and oppressed the late king's concubines
and his own half-brother
under the pretext
that they threatened the throne.
I will not live in disgrace like this!
Mother!
That year,
the king stained the court with blood
and filled the court
with his puppet Im Sa-hyeong
and officials who were his extensions.
And now,
he's leading Joseon toward its doom.
I knew that
his frank words had angered His Majesty,
but I didn't know
he went through all that in the palace.
There's no way you could've known.
The royal family
and the court officials covered it up.
And my lord also…
Why are you telling me this?
A child must know
their father's history.
Now, Lord Hong is at peace,
after enduring that ordeal.
So I'm telling you this story
out of joy and respect.
I see.
I met Gil-dong myself.
CATCH GIL-DONG
Word is spreading among the people
that Gil-dong has come back to life.
HONG EUN-JO
A godlike hero.
Perhaps…
we could use a god.
Bring me every rumor about Gil-dong.
It may not be wise
to ask the lord about the Gyeongo Year.
Let's eat.
Chicken soup?
You said you wanted to eat
the broody hen I cook.
What?
You scared me.
What's wrong?
Because you got only half
after the lord was served?
It's the broody hen again.
When did I ask you
to cook the broody hen for me?
Last time.
You're talking like a different person.
It was a different…
Never mind.
You've been looking upset.
Is everything all right?
I'm fine. Don't worry.
I know. I won't.
You told me
not to worry about you at all.
Did that person say that? Not to worry?
What else did you hear?
That person is you.
Did you forget?
You promised
that you would never lift a finger.
You promised that yourself.
Did you accept that promise?
Why are you sitting on the roof
every night these days?
Because I keep hoping
it will look smaller from here.
Why did you lie about the Royal School
just to turn Hong-si away?
Please do nothing.
That is the only way
to protect Eun-jo.
Do nothing.
You must protect your mother.
MARRIAGE
I forgot my place for a moment.
Are you not going to visit the leper camp?
I heard that you saw plague
spreading in the leper camp.
- Is that true?
- Yes.
So the plague spreading outside
started in the leper camp?
No, it is hard to say.
I'm the one to decide.
A plague.
It's a good pretext.
He said
I would never have to lift a finger?
As if.
He put all kinds of words in my mouth.
Eun-jo.
Did you forget something?
I thought you should know…
Well,
I overheard something while
I was drinking with Hwalinseo's slaves.
Overheard what?
They're shutting down
the leper camp tonight.
The order was
to pull it all down and burn it.
I feel so bad.
Physician Hong?
She said if I asked you for help,
you would know who to go to.
All right.
Everyone, wake up!
Wake up. Hurry.
Physician Hong?
We must get all the patients out now.
Geum-dol, go outside and wake everyone up.
Tell them they must all leave.
Should we really do this?
I'm an animal. Animals don't judge.
They only follow orders.
Do you think you can move?
Come with me.
What is going on?
I'll explain later.
We must get the patients…
Sir, your leg…
I got injured while hunting yesterday.
It's all right.
The soldiers are here already.
Wait here.
What's going on?
They've given the order to kill
all the sick here and shut the place down.
Run!
Run to the gate in the back!
Sun-dol!
- Wait there.
- It's too dangerous!
Finish it.
- Hold my hand.
- Go!
Just let my boy live.
Hold my hand now!
We could all die!
Please just go.
I'll come back. Wait here.
Physician Hong!
Hong Eun-jo.
Is this funny?
So many people nearly died,
all because of your family's greed.
You know where we are.
How could you do this?
I can't help it.
When I'm with you, I become fearless.
Gil-dong is alive.
You go to such lengths to protect him.
Gil-dong must be someone dear to you.
Make sure nothing about Gil-dong
is spoken of.
Please take care of it.
What about Your Highness?
Leave?
Where?
Subtitle translation by: Sunyoung Baek